[{"question":"<p><strong>The follow are the key factors which influenced Nigeria foreign relations except&nbsp;<\/strong><br \/><br \/><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["peaceful co-existence","economic dependence","non-interference","international co-operation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first African military coup in Egypt occured<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1951","1952","1953","1954"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not an accepted way of resolving international conflict?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["diplomacy","propaganda","military force","nuclear force"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Citizens who are legally qualified to vote for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["political parties","trade union congress","members of the House of Assembly","the electorate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Commonwealth is ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["an economic organisation","made up of all independent ex-colonies of Britain","made up of all countries who are friendly with Britain","made up of independent European countries"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first elected Executive President of Nigeria was<br \/><br \/><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shehu Shagari","Umaru Y'aradua","Nnamdi Azikwe","Olusegun Obasanjo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria became a federation of 19 states in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1996","1861","1976","1979"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under the 1979 Constitution, members of the Federal Executive Council were called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ministers","commissioners","senators","judges"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a unitary system of government<\/strong><br \/><br \/><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["parliament is very weak","there is high degree of centralisation","political power is diffused","there is low degree of centralisation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a means by which government maintains law and order<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["law making","maintenance of police and other security agencies","provision of socio-economic services","establishment of provisional association"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fascism emphasizes&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["equality","individualism","totalitarianism","communism"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Government by the few for the interest of the few is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["monarchy","dictatorship","autocracy","oligarchy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The doctrine of separation of powers is associated with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Locke","Marx","Montesquieu","Hobbes"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ECOWAS Monitoring Group (ECOMOG) was organised to maintain peace in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Guinea","Benin Republic","Liberia","Chad"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following principle officials of the house is not an elected parliamentarian?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["leader","speaker","clerk","chief whip"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A tax law emanates from<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the speaker","a public bill","a judicial bill","private bill"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The process through which people develop their political attitude is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["politicisation","political socialisation","political mobilisation","political dissemination"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not an agent of political socialisation?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["tourism","family","mass media","peer group"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Government can be described as the art of<\/strong><br \/><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["making constitutions","collecting taxes","engineering","making and enforcing laws"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An election in which people vote for issues of public policy rather than candidates is known as a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["main election","bye-election","party primary","referendum"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Power is transformed into authority through<\/strong><\/p>","options":["force","prayers","legitimacy","influence"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The concept of sovereignty was popularised by<\/strong><br \/><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["J.J. Rousseau","A.V. Dicey","C.L. Montesquieu","Jean Bodin"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Power under military rule in Nigeria can be said to be<\/strong><br \/><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><br \/><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["absolutely separated","absolutely fussed","more separated than fussed","absolutely centralised"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many Nigerians were elected into the Legislative Council when the elective principle was introduced in 1922<\/strong><\/p>","options":["two","three","four","six"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main deliberative organ of the UNO is the<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["International Court of Justice","Secretariat","Economic and Social Council","General Assembly"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following will produce weak government?<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["coalition","two-party system","general elections","military"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In democracies, political participation could be restricted on the basis of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["religion","class","race","age"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who founded the Unity Party of Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Ajasin","Pa Adesanya","Chief Falae","Chief Awolowo"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Free and fair election can exist where there is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["double voting","secret balloting","referendum","plebiscite"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Commission for Mediation, Conciliation and Arbitration is an organ of the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ECOWAS","AU","Commonwealth","OPEC"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first president of NIgeria Republic was&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Obafemi Awolowo","Nnamdi Azikwe","Ahmadu Bello","Ibrahim Babangida"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A federal constitution is usually<\/strong><\/p>","options":["flexible","unwritten","written and flexible","written and rigid"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One form of delegated legislation is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["case laws","statutory instruments","conventions","man-made laws"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The end of each session of the legislature is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dissolution","suspension","closure","prorogation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who among the following was dismissed from Action Group at the Jos Congress of February 1962?<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["Anthony Ehahoro","Ladoke Akintola","Dauda Adegbenro","Adesoji Aderemi"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The chief executive in a parliamentary government is known as the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["president","speaker","prime minister","governor-general"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Authority means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["an automatic right to be obey","legitimate right to obeyed","a civil right to obey orders","a civil right to be obeyed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Zionism resulted in the establishment of the state of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Iraq","Jordan","Israel","Lebanon"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>To promote justice in a state, judges must<\/strong><br \/><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["belong to the ruling party","punish people who oppose them","enjoy security of tenure of office","not socialise with the people"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The two main policies introduced by the French in West Africa were<\/strong><br \/><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["indirect rule and direct rule","indirect rule assimilation","direct rule and indignant","assimilation and association"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The scholar, who defined sovereignty as an absolute power vested in an authority was<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["A,V. Dicey","Jean Bodin","John Austin","Montesquieu"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The head of the Commonwealth of Nations is<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["Queen Elizabeth II","Don McKinnon","Tony Blair","David Cameroon"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following countries had practised confederated system of government?<\/strong><br \/><br \/><\/p>","options":["Senegal and Gambia","Mali and Senegal","Ghana and Nigeria","none of the above"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1978 Local Government Reform provided for a ... term of office<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4-year","5-year","2-year","3-year"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The exclusive list in a federal state includes<\/strong><\/p>","options":["education","market","defence","transportation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"}]